Hi. Can you hear me?
Yes, F. I can hear you. How are you?
I'm fine. And you? How you doing?
Uh, I'm fine, too. Um, I'm working here
in Mexico and try to looking for another
profile to Java Goland.
Okay,
this there is a good profile to be here.
Okay, thank you so much for your time,
Fabio, and for join with us today. you
have a technical interview and we have
with us Arthur Baj. He's our technical
interview viewer for this um process.
All right.
Okay.
Arthur, are you hear me?
Yes. Yes. Hello. Hello everybody.
Hello. How are you Arthur?
Fine, thanks. How about you?
Okay, I'm fine too. Okay, guys. Thank
you so much for your time and for
joining us to this uh technique
interview. So Fabio I left you with
Archur
Arur he is Fabio or candidate. So guys
thank you for your time from my side.
It's okay. I leave the session and if
you need something please let me know.
I'm going you on the chat. All right.
Okay. Perfect. Thank you.
Thank you. Have a nice day. Bye bye.
Okay. So hi Fabio. Nice to meet you.
Thank you for your time. And let me just
give a heads up on how this interview is
going to go. Right. uh first 5 to 10
minutes is for you to talk me a little
bit about your technical background and
specifically React Native experience
that you have. Uh after that I'm going
to ask you a couple of questions about
JavaScript and React Native and then we
are going to have a little code
challenge. Uh do you have any questions
for me?
No, no questions. First of all, hi
Arthur. It's nice to meet you to talk
with you too. Just a moment but I just
closed the window here.
Sure. No worries.
It's a lot of noise out there.
Okay, proceed.
Okay, so yeah, please you can get
started and tell me a little bit about
yourself.
Okay, I start my name is Fabio. I start
working with software development since
2010. I start work as a full stack
developer. In 2010, I start with PHP and
Java.
uh two years later I moved to another
company to start working only with PHP,
Java and my and my SQL database and
Postgres too. I used to work with an LMS
called Moodle. I do some type of
integrations. I use Laravel 2 in this
case to create some integrations and in
2018 I starting working with React and
React.
I started on this company for more two
years in end 2020 I moved to another
company again the company that I I was
currently working now it's called
Stephanini I start working as a native
iOS developer and but since I start
working in this company I work with
Android development too I start working
with Android and iOS native platforms
after two years working with these
platforms I started working with react
native again because the company starts
to migrating the native apps to
crossplatform apps. Some apps that
already exist are migrated and some
other apps are created in reaction
native and I still working in this
company now.
Okay, cool. Uh so can you dive in a
little bit about uh more technical
aspects of I mean the way you usually
architect the applications uh what do
you use for testing for instance uh
state management stuff like that? Okay,
in about state management man management
I use uh previously I use redux a lot
but today I was using more stand and
contest API I have more preference it's
just question of preferences and about
tests I use to create unit tests and
react library integration
tests and end to end tests Recently I
starting using my Astro and I think it's
a good tool to create integration tests
and end to end tests. Well, let me see
one more. I use SQLite and watermelon
DB. In some app, the majority of the
apps I use SQLite and some apps I was
using watermelon DB.
What more I can talk about about the
architecture? I when native apps I use a
lot MVVM in Android apps I use a lot of
native native Android apps I use a lot
MVVM in native iOS apps I use MVVM and
MVPC
in react native since it's a little bit
different from native apps I try to use
the the clear texture combine it with
redux or zand
Nice. And in terms of component
organization, uh can you tell me a
little bit about how do you architecture
the the components uh inside the
applications?
Yes, I can tell about that. At the first
moment when I work for the react native
for the first time, I was
Can you hear me?
Yes, I can hear you. Can you hear me?
Uh I I can't hear you for some reason. I
think you went mute there.
Can you hear me now?
Yes. Yes, I can. Okay, I I will speak
again. When I start working with
Reaction H, I separate my components by
types. For example, slicers, I have a
folder only for slicers, another folder
only for reducers and something like
that. But it quickly became a mess
because when I have for example five
files for reducers, it's good. But when
I need to have 20 or 30 files, it
becomes a mess. Can you hear me? Arthur,
Arthur, can you hear me?
Hey, sorry, my my VPN was acting up
here, so I had to disconnect it.
Okay, no problem. I I will speak again.
At first moment when I using I I
organize my folders with slicers,
another folder for reducers, but when I
have for example five files for
reducers, it's okay. But when I have 20
or 30, it start to become a mess.
Because of this, I stop using that
methodology and start creating my
components by features or screens some
people say because I have one screen of
the app and every my redues, my slicers,
everything goes inside this feature or
screen comp uh folder in everything goes
inside this part. I start component
start create components this way. now.
Okay. Nice. And uh last question. You
mentioned that you have uh it seems an
extensive experience on native
development, right? Do you have also the
experience on creating the bridge
between the native and react native?
Yes. Yes, I have
both. Go ahead.
Yes, I have the experience. One app that
I was developing, it's an app to
manipulate images. At the first moment I
was trying to find a plug-in that was
able to create some these effects on
image on react native but I was not able
to find a good plug-in or library for
that. In this case, I create a bridge to
in the case of the Android platform, I
create a B a bridge to use OpenCV to
manipulate images and but the results
are better than the plugin from React
Nature. But I am not satisfied yet with
results because of that. I use another
component to create this test this
images. But I is a pre-trained model
that I used with TensorFlow light to
create those image and the result was
much better. Because of this I implement
the same bridge in the iOS platform to
to continue to use TensorFlow flow light
and the pre-trained model and I still
looking for another pre-trained models
to implement more features on my image
app.
Oh, awesome. Okay. Okay. So, thank you.
That was all my questions. Uh so moving
on to to the questions uh about JS and
React Nate, right? I always start
simple. Uh so what can you tell me about
the difference between let and con in
JS?
Let con it's something that will never
change when it's when a value is
assigned to con it will never change.
Let I so just a moment I was mixing
something in my head about swift let and
the javascript let
just a moment in react native let is
something that is related to scope is a
variable related to scope different from
var that is have a that has a global
scope let only has a
function scope that you can assign a
parameter to
Okay, awesome. And what can you tell me
about the hoisting behavior in
JavaScript?
The hoisting behavior if I remember
correctly is when you declare some
parameters for example you declare
the function you can declare in this
function in any part of the code because
even if you call this function
create you create a function to call
this another function the function is
right in the bottom part of the code it
will still be read there's no problem
different from another language this
view can be read by the JavaScript file.
the the roasting in this case is that
becomes everything is read first in this
case of functions and has some special
considerations for parameters like var I
think the var if I remember correctly if
you declare it in the bottom part of the
file it will it will be read as
undefined if you try to call it before
it's assign it I think it's that as the
definition of hosting Awesome.
So, uh can you tell me what is a high
order function and one of its
applications in react native? I can
remember one high order function. It's
the reduce function. I I remember
another map function
filter function if I remember correctly.
Those are the three high order
functions. The reduce for example I can
use for example I can try to calculate
some values. I can res only instead of
create a loop for this I can just use
the reduce and make all the
multiplications or calculations inside
this reduce. The filter goes the same
way just like map I they you run inside
this brackets just like the reduce.
Okay, thank you. Uh on now on react what
can you tell me what's the difference
between use memo and use call back?
Use memo and use call back. Use call
back if I remember correctly is used to
not recall functions. For example, if I
use the use call back and try to render
the screen is rendered again, the use
call back will not trigger the function
again.
What is the other sorry I forget?
Use MIMO.
Use MIMO. I think it's for
functions and use MIMO. Just remember
just forget if I is for values but I
don't remember. It's for to say values.
I don't remember. I must make a
confusing about
me and use me. React.mimo
and use mimo. Just a moment please.
I think use use memo if to save
parameters from complex complex tasks
for example you need to calculate a lot
of different functions this you when I
use use MIMO this value is saved inside
the context
uh yeah that's pretty much that only
thing uh that was wrong was the use
callback right because both use memo and
use callbacks are used to memorize uh
something right the use memo used to
memorize the values that often need the
the the complex calculations, right? So
it doesn't get redeclared on every
hander. And they use callback. It's
pretty much the same thing, but we
declare functions using it, right?
Okay.
Uh so okay, moving on. Uh let me just
Oh, yeah. No, I have a couple of more
questions on React Native. Uh so can you
tell me some of the good practices uh
that we usually take into consideration
while developing React Native uh to not
affect the performance of the
application
to consider this life cycle of the
application. A lot of people just you
make a heavy use of the use effect. It's
not a good practice because it can
create side effects. The use effect is
use it just like the name says to create
side effects not to use for everything.
Let me see another good practice. I
think it's creating unit test to verify
the code. If we for example integration
tests and unit test to validate this
code I when I was writing a new feature
I could break a feature that is already
implemented in the code. This can help
guarantee that the code will not break.
When I was implementing new features
using state management, it's a good
practice.
Yeah, just just sorry, let me just uh
interrupt better because I I I mean just
good practice in terms of performance,
you know, just things that you do to
avoid any impact on performance.
Reaction native flat list is a good
example for from performance because
otherwise if I try to put in a scroll
view a scroll list is be
try to load the entire list for example
if I have 1,000 items it will render
everything at the moment that we it we
start if I have a flat list I won't it
won't it will only load the elements
that are visible in this screen. This
will affect performance greatly.
I think that's only the only one I can
remember now.
Uh well, you kind of already mentioned
to the the to the amount of paras right
by the users uh usage of the use effect
hook. Uh that would apply for any hook
literally that could trigger a hander.
But uh yeah uh so moving on uh to the
technical challenge here. Let me share
my screen real quick. Uh
just find again this tab.
Okay. Can you see this code here?
Yes.
Can you see it? Do I need to zoom in
here? Uh you can guide me here. Uh so
you can see better. Uh, is this size
enough? Do you want me to zoom in?
Sorry, just a moment, please.
I try to I just a moment. I try to
increase the size here. Okay.
What I Sorry, can you repeat what you I
need to what I need to do here? I don't
understand yet.
Uh, no, sure. At first, I just need to
know if you can read it well here. Yes,
I can. Do I need to to increase here the
the the zoom or to
No, I can read it now. I can read.
Hello.
Can you hear me?
Uh no, now I can hear you. Uh so I guess
we have some connection issues for now.
Sorry.
Okay, no problems. That happens.
Uh so first thing I need to know here is
uh can you see clearly this code here or
do I need to to to increase the zoom
here or can I just leave I can see here
I can see the code here.
Okay, perfect. So yeah, here I have uh a
quick app uh on react uh itself and
here's the entry point right the app
function and I have a component here
table that is right declared right here
on the top uh which is a memorized
component as you can see and here's I
have here I have another use memo and it
returns the table items that I have for
the table and this is another component
that is here on the top of the the file
here. So, uh getting back to the app
here, as you can see, I have a lots of
console logs here like uh on render, on
use effect, on the hooks that I'm using
here. There's on use call back and use
minimum here. And they all have on the
hander and the use effect here.
First thing I want you to do is to tell
me what are the of uh the the first
hander of the application is going to
log this uh console logs here. Uh so
take your time and if you need to take
notes uh feel free and guide me here if
you need me to go up and down the code
here.
I would think the first one will be the
console log a a append because it's just
the start of the app. Can you just a
moment?
AB can we scroll up please?
Mhm.
He's
using me more
up
table.
I can take this table item where it's
located. Can we scroll down, please?
table. I think
it's here.
Oh, it's really hard to guess this
because it's a lot of components inside
another one.
Let me see that. Can you scroll down
please?
Sure.
I view.
As you can see the first hander here
just have one array with the data with
only one item. So it's going to be just
uh app then table then table item at
first.
Okay. Even the
the use effect will be ignored at the
first time.
Well, that's part of the challenge
there.
Okay.
Okay. I think that's the case. The
the use effect will be called just
just a moment. The use effect will be
called first because the console log B
app mounted will be called first. Turn
the A the console log A
in in the handle click will not be
called hand click the console log C will
not be called it's now it's won't be
called if I click on the button so the
the first moment it will be the B A
can you scroll down please
down scroll down down here.
Yes, it's the table. Yes, you scroll up
now. B A Okay,
the table. I Yes, I to see the table
element GF.
It would be B. I think it's B A. If I
follow the same example from the below
GF because the use effect starts first
then the the element above above it
B A G F
table writing the H
B A G F H Can you scroll up please?
Mhm.
A G B A I I need to write that here. I
use the shed here.
I'm I'm putting the the I'm not sure if
you can see here. Let me zoom in or
increase the size.
Can you scroll down, please?
Uh, yes.
B A G F H
B A G F H.
I did. I can't just
I didn't get the last part. Come on. B A
D F H
B A F H
B I write
I write in the chat here.
Mhm.
Can you screw up please?
Sure.
E D. Okay. Just a moment. B A G F H
E and D E
I write in chat now. I think this will
be the the C will not be called unless
it's unless the it's clicked in the
button.
Mhm. That is correct. But let's check
here.
Uh so as you can see the use effect and
the the order of the render and use
effect was not correct. This is the log
here. Do I need to let me also
okay thanks for
it's I think the use effect will be will
be called first but it's not called
first.
It's it's just posit.
Yeah, it's actually yeah, it's first the
render here, right? And then this render
here and this H because this me is
declared and returned right away and
then this hander here and then it goes
running the use effects uh use effects
backwards, right? So this is effect runs
first and then this one after that one
and lastly uh the V here as you can see
it was just job positive that was that I
was thinking
yeah uh yeah so moving on um I want now
to for you to tell me there's a fact
sorry the console logs that are going to
appear if I click the button right now
uh as you can see I click the logs here
and I'm going to click this button right
okay
so what's what are going to be printed
out once I click there
and you click
it will you console log C will be will
be printed
Mhm.
I was thinking if something more the
it's it's use the MIMO
but I don't know it's using only MIMO
not
not use MIMO only react MIMO
just a moment
can you scroll up is
Mhm.
Memo will be called again or not.
I suppose
it was the first
the C letter will be will be printed and
the H letter the C and H letter.
H,
C, and H.
Mhm. Uh, okay. Only those two.
Yes. I I don't know if the use effect
will be target again. I
I don't know. Just a moment. If the use
effect
it will not rerender the entire screen.
Yes, just just those two.
Okay, so let's check that out.
Uh, and as you can see, there were two
handers on when I click that, right?
So, since I changed the state here, this
uh the render console logs since the
render runs again, you can see again the
the console logs, but you're right about
the use effect, right? No,
effects. Can you show me again please
the what is render?
C A F H. Okay. The C is correct.
The H is the last one and the use effect
is not colored again. But the console
log from the start is colored again.
Okay.
Yeah. The the the hander one. Okay. So
let's uh moving to the next one. As you
can see right now here I can click on
this button and the table is responsive
to that uh action. Right? However, if I
come here on the code
and I simply put another user state
here, const data set data
equals use state and I'm going to change
this here
to data here.
Uh so now if I refresh and click you can
see that the button is responsive but
the is no longer responsive here. So can
you tell me here what's going on? Why
that change uh affected the behavior in
that way?
Just a moment please let me think about
it.
Mhm.
I think because it's using con no
loading.
I really don't know why this is
affecting the app this way. At the first
moment I try to I maybe just guess
that's because it's a con value but it's
not correct because it's a using use
state but I really don't know how to
explain
date.
I can see there's there's something
wrong with data set data. It's because
Can you scroll up, please?
Uh there's another table data. It's some
type of shadowing. I don't don't know if
the con table already has a data value.
Maybe it's confusing because I don't
know if the names are being reused in
this case. Maybe I think maybe it's it's
because of this
Okay.
Okay. I got it. The loading is not being
the loading prop is not being passed.
Boolean loading. Okay.
Sorry, I can't hear you, Arthur.
It's on mute.
Oh, yeah. I was talking for so long here
on mute. Okay. Okay. So what was going
on here is that uh we were not comparing
right the memo function here from react
it receives two parameters. The first
one is the component and the second one
is the callback that is going to compare
the props. Since we're not comparing the
loading prop uh and the loading prop is
the only one that's changing here. The
data is no longer changing. Uh so that's
not going to trigger the hander of the
table that we need to see the update
right. uh why it was happening before
because every time it triggered a hander
and we had this declaration here right
on the hander right it was not assigned
it to any value or it was put on the now
that it's on the state it's memorized
right uh but since it was not memorized
before every time we had a hander here
it would get redeclared at this point
here and then the memorization would
consider that a change and would trigger
the the
uh child components there Okay.
Uh so, okay, moving on to the final part
of this challenge. I have here a file
called
uh API and I just mark here two API
methods. Uh I have a set timeout, right?
They all return two promises. The first
one fetch list returns an array of
numbers which is an array of ids, right?
And the second one is a fetch by ID. I
receive the ID as a parameter and I
resolve after uh this time out to this
database market database here right
according to the ID I'm going to return
this object
uh I want you to uh populate this table
with this data right here uh when the
user clicks the button here when the
clicks load data so when the user clicks
the load data I want to set the loading
to true and then run the asynchronous
calls and again uh set the loading to
file again so I can see the data there.
Uh what I want you to do to to focus on
this challenge, I want to focus on
performance here. So I need you to to
keep in mind uh anything uh try your
best to make the best usage of memory
and not triggering any handers and take
into consideration the timing of the
calls everything like that. I don't have
to worry uh naming stuff clean code uh
don't worry about that only zone
performance here.
Okay.
Uh so please uh don't speak too fast
because you're going to guide me in the
implementation here. So uh it's going to
you are going to tell me what I'm going
to write here so you can test it later.
Okay. Okay. Can you scroll up please?
The right the right the right part. Not
this. Yes. Okay. I need to show the
entire list for the first moment when
the is loading.
Yes, you need to load the all the data
there. Uh the 10 entries of the are the
today's
Okay, I will in this case I will try to
it's a promise I would call await fat
list.
It's showing I need to put a sync in
this function. I to be used await.
Mhm.
Okay.
Just a moment. Let me think.
Can you try to run the code to see it's
working at least the fat list? And no,
no, no, no. Try
Forget forget one thing. The load data
needs to be changed.
What can we scroll down please?
Uh here or here?
Yeah. And and it's okay. It's in the
left side. The data I need to change the
data here.
Fat list.
Can you
The set data value is fix it use state I
need to change it
but I don't know if yes I need to I
don't know if use fetch list here
directly if it will work or not
can you write just to see the fatly
instead of please comment this Find the
await fetch list and put the fat list
inside the use state.
The fat list call inside the US state.
What do you mean?
Yes.
Like this?
Yes, like this.
I think there's something
there's something wrong. But
do you want to run?
Yes. Try to run.
Okay.
But the map is not a function. Okay.
There's a river.
Can you just try to undo
Ctrl Z please?
Mhm.
Yes, it's okay. It's okay. I need to
have the ID and the name but the
fat list don't have
this. It's console log resolve
the resolve IG list. Where is the IG
list? H. Oh, it's a method that is
printed
this list. Okay,
it's going to be just this list here.
One through 10. It's going to be a
number of array, right? But one through
10.
If I write in this code, I try to to get
a console log in this IG list to see if
it work properly. Just like the ID and
name it's showing
uh okay where do you want the log to to
be added
the in below fetching list of ideas
the right side
here
okay it's it could be here
that is already and like here so
okay yes I didn't see it this I didn't
see this
yeah so yeah it's right here
okay can you
unfold. Please click the yes. Okay.
Now the the parameters are different
because of that it's giving an error in
the map of the data.
Can you return to the code please?
Mhm.
You need to pass two parameters in this
case to use state.
Just a moment. ID
promise fat list.
Just try to to run the code again to see
the fat fat list. Please
working properly.
matching list of ids a hand. Okay,
please go back to the code
the resolve.
This resolve keyboard is the ID list.
I I give up. I really don't know more
than that. I was not understand why the
resolve keyword is being used for in
this case.
Uh sure. So fetch list here is a a
promise, right? Is is this the the idea
here is to emulate a method a call to
the to a real API, you know?
So each of these methods are
asynchronous and they resolve uh with
this value here right uh after this time
out runs uh initially. So I set the time
out here to send milliseconds to sorry
to to 100 milliseconds here. Uh so this
is exactly what's going on here. And
this second method here receives an ID
as a parameter and resolves
uh to the entry of this object here
according to the ID. So if I run the ID
one here uh it's going to return the
shoe back name here only. So that's uh
what's going on. What we need to do here
on this handle is to do all the calls
required uh in a good way in a
performant way to populate the table
here.
Is that
yeah to to to set the data with uh all
the data that we need to to populate the
data here. Uh the table receives the
data which is an is an array of objects
containing ID and name. Right.
Okay.
This is this example is just the
I think you try to pass the data here.
It will be or it will be made some
shadowing in this case the data that is
in the use state. Please try to change
it to just data.
Yes, it's here.
Here. Yes.
No, it's not that.
I need to pass a meray here
that will contain all the
promises.
Try to pass the data inside brackets in
the US state to see.
No, it's not that. It's incorrect.
Let me see just a moment
set by IG.
I I really don't know. I give up.
Sure. No wor. Uh just to the idea here
was to create a function, right? the
that could return all the data that we
need. So since those are not methods
that we need inside the component,
right? I should not need to to declare
them inside the ender component. So that
would be the first thing that I uh would
not do here. Uh so we can optimize the
render method by not putting so much so
much logic into the render function. Uh
so right here we would have to uh I
don't know first we need to fetch the
ids right so uh we need to fetch uh
patch list
and then we need to fetch every name by
the the the ID right
we need yeah but we need to use promise
all so we can run them all at the same
time because if you just uh go like use
a for loop for for each here uh the
timeouts they are going to be uh lined
up right we don't want to queue with
those timeouts we want them all running
at the same time uh so to
all right it's going to
result
it's going to take an array of promises
right so I can just uh use the ids domap
here and return a promise here so Yeah.
Let me
I think this would be the best.
No, no, wait a minute. Not this.
I'm going to take the ID
and I'm going to return
a promise here. And I think function
uh and here I can await
the
patch by ID. For instance, fetch list.
No, patch by ID.
for each ID and con
item equals a weight and then I can just
return uh both the item and the no sorry
the name of the item
and the ID.
So if I'm not wrong this is okay I need
to also put in a weight here.
So now I have the name. Oh yeah, item
name here.
The result that I want and I just return
the result here. So on my handle click,
I just need to call that function that I
created
and then I set the data here
to
that. And let's see what's going wrong
here.
I'm returning a promise here.
Uh okay, that was kind of the idea. I
just need to check why is this a promise
here. But yeah, uh that was kind of the
challenge. I just need to wrap up the
all the promises in a promise. here so
we can have the best from the timeout of
the API itself and also to declare uh
this uh kind of function outside of the
hander method. Uh so yeah that
that concludes uh the interview today.
Do you have any questions for me?
Let let me see this
just a moment
about No, I I don't have questions at
the moment.
Okay, then. All right. So, thank you a
lot for your time, Fabio, and I wish you
the best of luck on your future
interviews.
Thanks. It was a pleasure to talk to
you, Arur. Thanks for for the
opportunity.
Thank you. Bye. Bye. Bye-bye.